Awais Tasleem

Address: 33 Worcester Street, Oldham OL9 7SE

Mobile No: 07457186802

E-mail: awaist7860@hotmail.com

LinkedIn Profile Link: https://www.linkedin.com/in/awais-tasleem-b1b27b180

My Online Portfolio: https://awaist7860.github.io/Awais-Portofolio/

My GitHub Page: awaist7860 (Awais Tasleem) (github.com)

Personal Profile

I am a Computer Science graduate from the University of Salford with a Second-Class Honours Division One grade. I am a passionate software enthusiast and skilled C# developer. I have experience creating games using the Unity Game Engine for the Google Play Store, developing websites and web applications, and creating bespoke software. My expertise includes C#, Java, PHP, JavaScript, and SQL.

Key Skills

• C#.NET	***	Linux (Ubuntu)	***
 ASP.NET 	***	 Windows Servers 	***
 VB.NET 	***	• Git	***
• C++	**	 Docker Containers 	**
 OpenGL 	**	 Kubernetes 	**
Java	***	 Databases 	****
• HTML	***	 Microsoft SQL Server 	****
CSS	***	 MYSQL Server 	****
 Bootstrap 	***	 MySQL Workbench 	****
 JavaScript 	***	 Unity Game Engine (C#) 	****
jQuery	***	 Blender 3D Modelling 	**
PHP	***	 Active Directory 	****
 Node.JS 	**	 vSphere 	***
 SQL/MYSQ 	L ***	• Citrix	***
• Bash/Term	inal ★★★	 SQL Server Management Studio 	***

 \star = Basic $\star \star \star \star$ = Advanced

Employment History

IT Placement Student at Knorr-Bremse Rail System, UK

12th July 2021 till 22nd July 2022

Experience Gained:

- IT admin tasks using Active Directory.
- Setting up machines and phones for clients.
- Talking with customers and trying to get a solution from their problem.
- Working on tickets.
- Project work (Security Project, VPN Project, Windows upgrades, Selling Old IT equipment)
- Working with external companies on projects.
- Setting up networks and VLANS.
- Building and configuring servers.
- Making VDI's and setting up Citrix for them.
- Documenting all my work
- Repairing broken machines.

Phone Repair Technician at King Communications

2016 till 2018

Experience Gained:

- Repairing pretty much anything, from phones, consoles to TVs.
- Learning how to use batch scripts to automate my workflow and make me more efficient.
- Working in a productive environment.
- Talking with customers and trying to get a solution from there problem.
- Managing repairs.
- Managing employees below me and working with them in a team environment.

Warehouse Manager at Imperial Beddings.

2017 - 2020

Experience Gained:

- Understanding how the logistics of goods work.
- Making a good network with suppliers and negotiating with big companies.
- Maintaining orders and using a JIT service.
- Understanding the stock management system and how all the servers link together.
- Managing 3 different warehouses from a central office.
- Maintaining security equipment such as cameras and recorders.

Interests

- Gaming: Love to play games such as Call of Duty or Battlefield, either on my PC or Console.
- Tech Enthusiast: I stay updated on the latest CPU and GPU news.
- Fitness: Regular gym-goer (3 days/week) focusing on weight loss and muscle gain.
- Travel: Love to travel around the world.
- Cars: I am a car enthusiast and have a passion for JDM and personal project cars.

Education

University of Salford

Bachelor's degree in computer science with Professional Experience

Grade - Second Class Honours Division One

Oldham Sixth Form College

2016-2018 Computer Science, ICT and Business

Blessed John Henry Newman RC College

English - C

Maths - B

References

Available upon request